I wish I had known this earlier that just such a
small mistake
resulted in the
car insurance claim getting rejected. The
reasons for rejection of this claim should be known only to you. Your
claim can be approved and the
insurance company will not
get the chance to reject you alone.
So what are the main reasons for car claim rejection
and how can you avoid your claim getting
rejected by them?
In today's video, we will learn all this. Let's
start the video. The first reason is friends,
delay in claim intimation, that is, informing the
insurance company about the accident or loss. It is a
loss, so we think that if
we have insurance, then
we will get the claim anyway, but we do not
understand that while taking a claim, if there is an accident, the
car gets stolen, there is a damage
to the car, any damage occurs,
we have to immediately inform the insurance
company about it on its toll free number.
While filing the claim, give them the correct information
and going forward, whenever your claim is
processed, do not make any changes in it.  If you contact the
company tomorrow, then
definitely tell them that if
any officer from the insurance company wants to come to the spot and do a spot survey or
assess the damage, then he
can do it, otherwise you must capture
it through photos and videos in your phone.
If we
inform the insurance company from the diary, then due to such
small checks, they can make a mistake and
reject our claim. The
second reason is friends, Rang NC in policy.
NC means No Claim Bonus, you already know this,
it is a kind of discount which the insurance
company
gives you in exchange for not taking a claim,
it increases with every claim free air,
after the first claim free air you will
get 20% MC,
45 is
its top
slab, whichever year you take a claim,
your MC will again come to 0, but
in the insurance policy, everyone wants discounts, they will
change to another insurance company and we will
not tell them that we have taken a claim and we will take the discount of our No Claim Bonus, at
least the policy will be cheaper,
but my friend, it will be made available to the police, but
when a claim comes, the survey cost which would have been less earlier  It
verifies NC from your policy, that is, it finds out from
your old insurance
companies whether the
no claim bonus you have taken is correct or
not, that is, whether you have taken any claim in the old policies
and if it is found
that you have
taken a bonus in your job by making a wrong declaration, then
some part of the claim or even the entire
plan can be rejected. Do
not make such a mistake for a small discount. If
you have made a claim, then inform the insurance company
and take only the
no claim bonus that you are eligible for and do
not take MC discount with wrong information so that you do not face any
problem in the claim in future. The next
reason is friends, ownership transfer. I purchased a
used car, that is, I bought an old car
and got the
RC done, but
I think that when I get this policy renewed,
then I will register my name in it,
but you should not do this. Whenever
your name is updated in your RC,
you have to immediately get the same name updated in your insurance policy, only then
you will
get coverage under this policy. With the
endorsement of human transfer  For this, there is a small
process in which your vehicle
will be inspected and the cost for this is
only Rs 50 to 100.
Apart from this, if your previous owner has
taken up a job, then
you may have to pay that also back to the company
because you will have to increase your new no claim bonus
from zero again and after this process,
your name will also be updated in the insurance policy
because all the details which are mentioned in the RC, the same
details will be mentioned in the policy
and there will be no problem in your plan.
Friends, the next reason is multiple
damages, mother, the front bumper of my car is
broken, the left side window is
also broken, after some time the
rear window is broken, friends, first of all these are damaged, so can
I claim these three damages in one insurance claim,
no, that claim will be rejected.
Many times we think that why should I claim
separate claims for small claims,
when three-four damages happen together, then we will
claim in insurance.
And the car will be repaired as well, but this is not the case. The
eligibility for insurance company's claim is only for the latest damage, that is, the
insurance company will cover only the most recent damage. And one thing is that if a
part which is already damaged gets
damaged again, then the insurance
company will not accept that claim. For example, your
bumper is the
front part of your car, a
part of it is broken from a corner, and
in a major accident, a
major part of that bumper gets broken again, then the
insurance company will reject that insurance claim as well. You
say that
your bumper was already broken before this damage, that is, it was
broken. The reason given by the insurance company is that
our
liability is only to replace the new part if it breaks. If the
broken part
breaks again, we will not cover the damage.
Secondly, we have also heard many times
that both sides of the car are not covered.
Suppose your car gets damaged from the front
and rear simultaneously, if both the left and right
sides get damaged simultaneously, then
that will not be covered. It is not so.
You can get clamps for both sides.  But
in nine out of ten cases, these are
damages that occurred at different times, i.e., it was first damaged from the front
and later damaged from the rear. So, we go to get it
repaired and want to treat it as a single
damage. If your
car is damaged from both sides at the same time, then
definitely take photo or video proof of it.
[Music] I
mean, one damage occurred at a different time and the
second damage to the other side occurred at a different time, then there is
definitely a problem in the plane.
So what should you do? There is a lot of
confusion in this. What if
something
happens to the car?
Obviously, you should not claim it in the insurance. You will get it
repaired from your pocket. But the damage that you have to
claim in the insurance,
claim it at the time when that damage occurred. Do
not wait for me to make
another claim. If any damage occurs that you feel
you should claim,
file a claim for it immediately and get it done.
If any other damage occurs and you
feel that it needs to be claimed, then get it
repaired on time and collect all the three damages
together.  Don't make the mistake of making a claim, your
claim may get rejected. The next
reason is that CNG is
not updated in your insurance policy. Friends, CNG
is a good alternative to petrol.
Your vehicle will give good mileage and pollution will
also be less. Whenever you get CNG installed in your vehicle from outside,
you get it added to your RC after getting it passed in the RTO,
but you do not get it added to the insurance. There can be a
problem in the claim here
because if a claim is made in the
future and the insurance
company surveys it and sees
that CNG is installed inside the vehicle
but there is no CNG details edited in the insurance policy,
then there can be a
problem in the claim. There is no lengthy process for getting CNG added. There is a
small process in
which your vehicle
will be inspected and the value of your CNG, the
invoice value of the amount for which you have installed the CNG, its coverage will also be
given in the insurance policy, that is, at the
time of any loss, your CNG will also be included
in the insurance policy.  This is
also beneficial for you. Whenever
you get CNG installed in your vehicle, get it
endorsed.
You may have to pay some extra money for it
because the value of CNG is
adding extra coverage to your insurance policy.
So, just get the CNG added to the RC and
leave it. It is absolutely certain that there will be problems in the claim. Get it
endorsed
and do not leave it. The
next reason is that friends,
original images of the vehicle are required in a car theft claim. Whenever
you file a claim for a major theft,
its process can be a bit long and
complicated. What is the reason?
There is an inward process like
submitting an untraceable report.
This takes time. On top of that, the
surveyor's questions can trouble you.
But a very important
part of it is the original keys of the vehicle. When you
meet the surveyor and you ask him questions,
he will definitely ask for the original keys of the vehicle. He
wants to check whether
your negligence was involved in the theft of the vehicle or the person who
stole the vehicle.  It is yours
only with your keys
because IRDA has the right to
deny your claim if you are not present with the original key of the vehicle.
However, these guidelines are there that
if the vehicle is stolen due to your negligence, to
avoid such a rejection, first of all,
if the original key of your vehicle is
lost in some paste, you should
inform the police and get it replaced
because it is
quite common for the key to get damaged. If you get it replaced, first of all
try to get the key mentioned
in your insurance policy and get it
replaced from its undertaking.
Secondly, if you get it replaced with your own money, then keep
some proof of it like
its en-voice or any
proof of getting the key changed with you so that you can
prove that you had made the original investment
and at what time it was done. If
you give them the proof of that, then there will be
no problem in your claim. However, you
can also challenge it legally. If you do not have the
original key, it is
not that
a claim will be rejected just because it is damaged.  You
can challenge it legally and
you can also get your claim. If you
want to see the details related to the original champions, then if you want to
deal then click on the link on the i button. So
friends, now you have learned all the important reasons
which may sound very
small but due to these
even big claims can get rejected.
Now with the information, your
clip will be made.
Then the channel will ensure that no genuine
claim, a valid claim, gets
rejected due to lack of information. That we did
not know anything, due to this our claim got
rejected even though we have paid the full amount of the policy,
our loss is also
dear, but due to our mistake, our
lack of awareness, that claim gets
rejected. I am very
upset with it. So friends,
if you liked the information given in the video, you understood it
and if you feel that it will be less for you, then
like the video immediately and subscribe to the channel.
I am Harvinder Singh. I am late with you now, I will meet
you in the next video
with more information topics. Till then take
care of yourself, stay happy and healthy.  Stay, Jai
Hind
[Music]